bowl.com 2013-05-13

# BOWL.com | Privacy

**BOWL.com Privacy Policy**

Last updated on August 1, 2012 

United States Bowling Congress, Inc. (“USBC” and sometimes referred to as “we,” “us,” or “our”) appreciates your interest in our website, **WWW.BOWL.COM** (the “Site”).  Your privacy is important to us.  In connection with providing the information and services available at the Site, there are times when we may ask for or collect information from you, either in the form of anonymous data or personally identifiable information.  As part of our commitment to honoring your privacy, this Privacy Policy explains the approach we take in protecting and using the information that we gather from you on our Site.  This Privacy Policy is incorporated in the Site’s [Terms of Service](http://www.bowl.com/tos/ "Terms of Service"). 

_**Types of Information We Collect  **_ 

**Cookies:** When you visit the Site, we ask your browser to store small text files containing a string of alphanumeric characters known as a cookie.  We use both session cookies and persistent cookies.  If you have chosen to identify yourself on a Site, we use session cookies containing encrypted information to identify you and facilitate your use of the Site. Session cookies are required to access much of the content and services offered on the Site.  After you leave our Site and close your browser, a persistent cookie remains. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your help file directions in your web browser.  If you refuse our cookies, some features of the Site may not function properly for you.

 **User Provided Information:** When you choose to submit personally identifiable information to our Site (including your name, address, phone number, membership number, league number, email address, birth date, location), your information is maintained and used only in accordance with this Policy or as required by law.  In many cases, you choose the amount of information you supply.  There may be instances where some of the information that we ask you to provide is identified as mandatory and some as voluntary.  In such cases, if you do not provide mandatory personal information with respect to a particular activity, you will not be able to engage in that activity. We may collect personally identifiable information when you:

We collect personal information from visitors to our Site on a voluntary basis; however, visitors are not required to give such information to access many portions of our Site.  Personal information may include, without limitation, name, address, phone number, membership number, league number, birth date, location data and e-mail address.  A user’s personal information may be used for purposes of responding to inquiries or requests from users of the Site. 

When someone visits the Site, our web servers automatically gather information that allows the Site to communicate with the visitor’s computer during the visit.  We also may use any of the following information: the number of visits to the Site, which parts of the Site visitors select, IP address (the Internet address assigned to your computer from your Internet service provider), domain type, browser type (e.g., Safari or Internet Explorer) and date and time of day.  We use this information for statistical purposes that help us design and administer the Site.  We may also use this information to determine the validity of reviews posted on the Site.  Those types of information do not disclose personally identifiable information that would permit us to identify or locate individual visitors. 

_**Disclosure of Information**_

As a general matter, we do not sell, trade or rent to any unaffiliated third parties your personally identifiable information collected on our Site.  We do, however, provide and in certain circumstances sell personal information collected on our Site to our marketing partners for purposes of sending you promotional offers and notices of products and service offerings which we believe may be of interest to you.  We do use the anonymous data and the personally identifiable information collected through our Site for statistical purposes and for improving the Site, as well as for our marketing purposes, as part of our responses to your questions or requests for information, in response to comments or other content posted by a Site user, and potentially when sending commercial emails to you.  We may engage a third party’s software or services to assist us with these analyses and activities in which case such information may be shared with them for these purposes (e.g., your email address with our outbound email marketing provider).   

We may contract with other companies to provide certain services such as email distribution, market research, and promotions management.  We provide these companies with only the information they need to perform their services and work closely with them to ensure that your privacy is respected and protected.  This may include sending you emails periodically.  However, you will have the choice to opt out of receiving promotional emails for our services.  These companies are prohibited by contract from using this information for their own marketing purposes or from sharing this information with anyone other than us.   

If we or our assets are sold or transferred or used as security, the information collected on our Site may be transferred or shared with third parties as part of that transaction.  Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this Privacy Policy, we may also disclose personally identifiable information in order to respond to a subpoena, court order or other similar request or legal process.  We may also provide such personally identifiable information in response to a law enforcement agency’s request, as otherwise required by law, or if we believe, in our reasonable judgment, that providing such information is necessary for us to avoid criminal or civil liability. 

_**Security Measures**_  

We use a variety of current technologies and processes for protection of our customer data.  We maintain a private database on our web server for the storage of all information collected through our Site.  It is our practice to use encryption whenever we receive or transmit sensitive data.  We will take reasonable measures which we believe are appropriate to protect your information from loss, misuse, alteration or destruction, and, where possible, will ask that any third parties to whom we may transfer your information take comparable steps to protect that security.  Although we will use all reasonable efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of any visitor information collected, we shall have no liability for disclosure of any visitor information obtained due to errors in transmission or the unauthorized acts of third parties.  Email is not a secure form of communication.  Please do not send us any personally sensitive information via email.

 _ **Other Websites**_  

This Privacy Policy only applies to the Site.  Please be aware that the Site and email communications may contain links to other websites on the Internet. The information and privacy practices of those websites linked to our Site, including websites directly affiliated with us or the Site, are not covered by this Privacy Policy and, therefore, we are not responsible for the content or privacy policies of websites to which our Site links.  We encourage you to review the privacy policies of other websites to understand their privacy practices. 

_**Public Forum**_

Any information you submit in a public forum (e.g., a post in a user forum on the Site, a blog, chat room, or social network) can be read, collected, or used by us and others, and could be used to personalize your experience. You are responsible for the information you choose to submit in these instances.  Such user-posted material is not subject to this Privacy Policy.

 _ **Who May Use Our Site**_  

Our Site is designed for users from the United States.  Users from other countries are advised not to disclose personal information unless they consent to having their information used as set forth in this Privacy Policy, rather than under the law of user’s home country.  You should not send any personal information to the Site unless you agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy and by United States and any applicable state laws. 

_**Children**_  

We do not knowingly collect personal information from people younger than the age of 13. Minors may only use the Site and purchase a membership with the consent of their parent or guardian.  Minors may only submit personal information to the Site with the consent of their parent or guardian. 

_**Opt Out/Modify Information**_  

If you would like to add your name to our marketing list, request that your name be removed, or correct your current information, please write us at: [bowlinfo@bowl.com](mailto:bowlinfo@bowl.com).   

Please include your full name and email address in case we have any questions.  You can also opt-out of receiving email communications from us by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link in our emails.  We will make a reasonable effort to accommodate your request. 

This Site includes a feature which allows users to search for registered members and find out, among other information, the location of that member’s local association.  If you are a registered member and would like to remove your information, including location of your local association, please contact us at: [bowlinfo@bowl.com](mailto:bowlinfo@bowl.com).   

_**Changes and Updates to this Privacy Policy**_

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time and at any time without notice to you by posting modifications to this Privacy Policy at the Site.  By using the Site following such changes, you agree to be bound by such changes.  Please check the Site periodically to familiarize yourself with any changes that may have been made to this Privacy Policy.  You can determine when this Privacy Policy was last changed by checking the “Last Updated” reference above.
